ANDREI NECULAI

Bucharest, Romania | +40 727 843 344 | neculaiandrei@hotmail.com linkedin.com/in/andrei-neculai | github.com/neculaiandrei

PROFILE

Software Developer with 10+ years of experience in developing web applications using .NET / Node.js ecosystems. Consider myself to have an eye for details and a thirst for knowing everything about the product I'm working on. Enjoy optimizing backend/frontend performance.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: C#, Javascript, Typescript, SQL

Frontend: AngularJs, React

Backend: Node.js, .NET/.NET Core, ASP.NET, NancyFx, Sequelize, Dapper

Databases: Microsoft SQL Server, Postgres, Redis

DevOps/Cloud: Containerization, Kubernetes, AWS, AppVeyor, CircleCI, Github Actions

Others: Git, GraphQL, LiquidJS, FFmpeg

WORK EXPERIENCE

ATELIERE CREATIVE TECHNOLOGIES

Bucharest, Romania (Remote)

Backend Developer

Feb 2022 - Present

Developed and maintained a web application used for media supply chain management. Backend is built using Node.js and runs in Docker containers as part of a Kubernetes cluster. The API is built with GraphQL. PostgreSQL for storage.

- Extended functionality for generating metadata files using LiquidJS template engine.
- Added functionality for trimming/stitching video files using AWS MediaConvert / Dolby Hybrik.
- Added functionality for thumbnail extraction using FFmpeg.
- Various improvements in organizing and delivering media assets.

MOOD MEDIA Bucharest, Romania (Hybrid)

Full Stack Developer

Apr 2017 – Jan 2022

Developed and maintained a web application used for managing advertisement content. Backend was built using .NET (.NET 4.6 to .NET Core 3.1) and AngularJs/React for frontend.

- Improved performance of multiple API endpoints by optimizing SQL queries and code refactoring.
- Improved frontend performance when rendering lists/trees/grids with large amounts of data.
- At the end of Q3 2018, I led the transition of new dev colleagues into the team, as previous ones changed teams. For a few months, it was a rewarding challenge to solve support issues with minimal help and to share knowledge with colleagues.

EQUILOBE SOFTWARE

Bucharest, Romania (On-site)

Full Stack Developer

May 2015 – Mar 2017

Developed and maintained a web application used for employers' risk inventory. Backend was built with .NET 4.5. NHibernate for data access. Frontend used vanilla JavaScript and in-house frameworks.

- Created a questionnaire wizard with plain Javascript and prototypical inheritance.
- Assisted in migrating the web framework from Castle Monorail to ASP.NET MVC.

SWIRO

Bucharest, Romania (On-site)

.NET Developer Jul 2013 – Apr 2014

Contributed to the development of a desktop application for fiber management. Application was developed using WPF. Entity Framework Code First for data access.

EDUCATION

BUCHAREST UNIVERSITY, FACULTY OF MATHEMATICS AND COMPUTER SCIENCE

Bucharest, Romania 2014 - 2016

Master Degree

Major in Software Engineering

Admission GPA: 9.81/10; Years GPA: 9.06 / 10

Graduation project was exploring how isomorphic javascript can be achieved.

BUCHAREST UNIVERSITY, FACULTY OF MATHEMATICS AND COMPUTER SCIENCE

Bucharest, Romania 2011 - 2014

Bachelor Degree

Major in Computer Science

Admission GPA: 8.33/10; Years GPA: 8.23 / 10

Graduation project was a web application where multiple users could test their general knowledge against each other by doing quiz in real time.